{
  "quiz_data":[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "How much has the average global temperature risen by since 1880 (in Fahrenheit)?",
      "options": ["0.5 degrees", "1.69 degrees", "5 degrees"],
      "type": "mcq",
      "answer": 2,
      "fact": "The average global temperature has risen by 1.69 degrees F (0.94 degrees C) since the twentieth century with more significant warming toward the poles than in the equatorial region."
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which is the first specie to go extinct due to human-driven climate change?",
      "options": ["Golden Toad", "Bramble cay melomys"],
      "type": "mcq",
      "answer": 2,
      "fact": "A small rodent that lived only on a single island off Australia is likely the world's first mammal to become a casualty of climate change, scientists reported in June 2016. The government of Australia has now officially recognized the Bramble Cay melomys (Melomys rubicola) as extinct."
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Wasting less food is a way to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.",
      "options": ["True", "False"],
      "type": "True_or_False",
      "answer": 1,
      "fact": "More than a third of food produced globally never makes it to the table. Some of this wasted food spoils  in transit, while consumers throw some of this food out. During the production, harvesting, transporting, and packaging of the wasted food, more than 3.3 billion metric tons of carbon dioxide is emitted."
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following is a greenhouse gas?",
      "options": ["Carbon Dioxide", "Methane", "Water vapour", "All of the above"],
      "type": "mcq",
      "answer": 4,
      "fact": "Greenhouse gases may be a result of natural occurrence or human activity. These gases include water vapor, carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, and ozone. Fluorinated gases are also considered to be greenhouse gases."
    },
    {
      "id":5,
      "question":"What is the Greenhouse Effect?",
      "options":[
        "The name of climate change legislation that passed by congress",
        "When you paint your house green to become an environmentalist",
        "When the gasses in our atmosphere trap heat and block it from escaping our planet",
        "When you build a greenhouse"
      ],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"The Earth receives solar radiation from the sun. Passing through the atmosphere, some radiation is absorbed by the Earth, while some is reflected back to space. When the exchange of incoming and outgoing radiation occurs, some of the radiation becomes trapped by gases in the atmosphere. This creates a â€œgreenhouseâ€ effect and warms the planet."
    },
    {
      "id":6,
      "question":"The overwhelming majority of scientists agree that climate change is real and caused by humans. ",
      "options":["True", "False"],
      "type":"True_or_False",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Studies show that 97 percent (or more) of climate scientists who are actively publishing agree that climate change is likely due to human activity.  Nearly 200 scientific organizations across the globe have issued statements that publicly endorse this view."
    },
    {
      "id":7,
      "question":"Which of these countries emits the most carbon dioxide?",
      "options":["China", "USA", "UK", "Russia"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"According to the EPA, China is currently the top emitter of carbon dioxide, accounting for 30% of global carbon emissions. The United States ranks as the second top emitter at 15%."
    },
    {
      "id":8,
      "question":"What percentage of the global greenhouse gas emissions does the transportation sector emit?",
      "options":["1%", "14%", "33%", "70%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"The transportation sector emits 14% of global greenhouse gas emissions. Most of this involves fossil fuels burned for road, rail, air, and marine transportation, since petroleum-based fuels (i.e., gasoline and diesel) account for almost all of the worldâ€™s transportation energy."
    },
    {
      "id":9,
      "question":"Globally, which of the following economic sectors emits the largest percentage of greenhouse gas emissions?",
      "options":["Transportation", "Buildings", "Industry", "Electricity and heat production "],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":4,
      "fact":"The electricity and heat production sector emits the largest percentage of global greenhouse gas emissions at 25%. Agriculture, forestry, and other land use sector is a close second at 24%."
    },
    {
      "id":10,
      "question":"No place on Earth is colder today than it was 100 years ago.",
      "options":["True", "False"],
      "type":"True_or_False",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"Although most locations on the planet have recorded increased temperatures since 1900, changes in global ocean and atmospheric circulation patterns have created small-scale temperature decreases in a few local regions."
    },
    {
      "id":11,
      "question":"As average global temperature rises, Average precipitation _________",
      "options":["increases", "decreases", "remains unchanged"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Higher temperatures give rise to a more active water cycle, which means faster and greater evaporation and precipitation and more extreme weather events."
    },
    {
      "id":12,
      "question":"Compared to other greenhouse gases, carbon dioxide is the most effective at trapping heat near the Earth's surface.",
      "options":["True", "False"],
      "type":"True_or_False",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"Water vapor actually has more heat-trapping power than carbon dioxide. It is also more abundant. But carbon dioxide and water vapor interact in crucial ways: More carbon dioxide means the atmosphere gets warmer, which then creates more water vapor, which traps heat and warms the atmosphere even more."
    },
    {
      "id":13,
      "question":"Earth has been warmer in the past than it is today.",
      "options":["True", "False"],
      "type":"True_or_False",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Global temperatures during some of the past interglacial periods have exceeded the average temperatures we observe today, although you would have to go back more than three million years to find a period that was clearly warmer than today. Temperatures in the most recent decade have now exceeded the warmth of the previous Eemian interglacial."
    },
    {
      "id":14,
      "question":"Compared to 1750, how much more carbon dioxide is in our air today?",
      "options":["40%", "No Change", "150%", "20%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Not in the history of mankind has carbon dioxide levels reached such high levels. Research from ancient ice cores show that the last time carbon dioxide levels were this high, millions of years ago, our species had not yet even evolved."
    },
    {
      "id":15,
      "question":"The origin of The ICEMAN is:",
      "options":["Iceland", "Ice-cream", "Ice-cube", "Iced-tea", "None of these."],
      "type":"**crazy**",
      "answer":0,
      "fact":"ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»ğŸ‘»"
    },
    {
      "id":16,
      "question":"The season in which lemon's beared shines:",
      "options":["Summer", "Winter", "I dont know", "All seasons", "Never"],
      "type":"**crazy**",
      "answer":0,
      "fact":"**Come on guys, SPAM the answer in the TWITCH chat!**"
    },
    {
      "id":17,
      "question":"What % of climate scientists agree that human activities are causing climate change?:",
      "options":["97%", "55%", "63%", "24%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":0,
      "fact":"According to NASA: â€œMultiple studies published in peer-reviewed scientific journals show that 97 percent or more of actively publishing climate scientists agree: Climate-warming trends over the past century are very likely due to human activities. In addition, most of the leading scientific organizations worldwide have issued public statements endorsing this position.â€"
    },
    {
      "id":18,
      "question":"How much has our planet warmed already, on average in degrees Celsius? :",
      "options":["1.5", "2.0", "0.5", "1.0"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"According to the BBC in 2015: â€œFigures from January to September this year are already 1.02 degrees Celsius above the average between 1850 and 1900. If temperatures remain as predicted, 2015 will be the first year to breach this key threshold. The world would then be half way towards 2 degrees Celsius, the gateway to dangerous warming.â€"
    },
    {
      "id":19,
      "question":"How much more acidic are our oceans today? :",
      "options":["11%", "20%", "5%", "More than 26%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"This speed of ocean acidification is also the fastest recorded in the past 65 Million years! According to the United Nations IPCC report: â€œOcean acidification is quantified by decreases in pH. The pH of ocean surface water has decreased by 0.1 since the beginning of the industrial era (high confidence), corresponding to a 26% increase in hydrogen ion concentration.â€"
    },
    {
      "id":20,
      "question":"Sea levels rose by 19cm between 1901 and 2010. How fast are they continuing to rise? :",
      "options":["Rising at the same rate as before", "Rising faster, but sea levels will rise by no more than 1 m by 2100", "Rising faster, with the likelihood of multi-meter rise in the next 50-150 years"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"The United Nations expected sea levels to rise by no more than 1 metre by 2100, however recent research in 2016 published in the journal â€˜Natureâ€™ states that this is too conservative, and that without decisive action to cut carbon now, â€œmulti-meter sea level rise would become practically unavoidable, probably within 50â€“150 years.â€ This new research by noted climatologist Dr. James Hansen references a similar period in the Earthâ€™s prehistoric past, where sea levels reached +6â€“9m during a period that was â€œno more than a few tenths of a degree warmer than today.â€"
    },
    {
      "id":21,
      "question":"Compared to 1750, how much more carbon dioxide is in our air today? :",
      "options":["No change", "40%", "100%", "150%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Not in the history of mankind has carbon dioxide levels reached such high levels. Research from ancient ice cores show that the last time carbon dioxide levels were this high, millions of years ago, our species had not yet even evolved."
    },
    {
      "id":22,
      "question":"Compared to 1750, how much more methane is in our air today? :",
      "options":["No change", "40%", "100%", "150%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"Much of this comes from our intensive animal agricultural sector (belching from cows and sheep in particular, and rotting manure)."
    },
    {
      "id":23,
      "question":"How much more powerful is methane at warming our planet up, compared to carbon dioxide? (measured over 20 years):",
      "options":["25X", "42x", "84x", "10x"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"Methane is 84x more powerful than carbon dioxide at warming, when measured over 20 years. Because it is such a potent gas, we can make a big difference in the short term by cutting large sources of methane, like making energy companies responsible for stopping leaks from gas pipelines."
    },
    {
      "id":24,
      "question":"What is a â€œsafeâ€ level of greenhouse gas concentration in our air? :",
      "options":["350 ppm", "400 ppm", "450 ppm", "500 ppm"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":0,
      "fact":"A stable level of 350 parts per million in our air is expected to lead to around 1.5 degrees Celsius of warming. But, weâ€™ve already broken past 400 parts per million as of 2016, and weâ€™re still rising. At 450 parts per million, scientists expect a 2-in-3 chance or more of warming by 2 degrees Celsius. To bring this back down to a safe level, we need to plant trees to absorb carbon dioxide from the air, and cut down our emissions to zero so we stop pumping more into the air. The good news? We have lots of solutions to do just this. The bad news? Not enough of us are convinced we need to change."
    },
    {
      "id":25,
      "question":"Is nuclear power a low-carbon energy source? :",
      "options":["Yes", "No"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":0,
      "fact":"According to the United Nations, in order to generate the same amount of energy, nuclear power generally uses LESS carbon than solar PV or geothermal power sources. It uses about the SAME carbon as biomass and wind power sources, but MORE than hydropower sources. According to the Renewable Energy Network REN21, nuclear provided 2.5% of the worldâ€™s energy used in 2015, compared to 1.4% provided by wind, solar, biomass and geothermal power sources combined. Itâ€™s clear that we need to scale up our renewable energy sources like wind and solar, but equally clear that to have any hope of weaning ourselves off fossil fuels (which provided around 80% of the energy we used in 2015), we need to use every low-carbon energy source we have."
    },
    {
      "id":26,
      "question":"Did you know 30% of our electricity in 2010 came from low-carbon sources? To limit warming to 2 degrees Celsius, by 2050 this needs to increase to :",
      "options":["40%", "50%", "70%", "More than 80%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"According to the United Nations, in order to stay on track for 2 degrees Celsius, we need to aggressively cut carbon, and a key milestone is to boost how much low-carbon electricity we use. This means diversifying away from dirty coal, oil and even gas, towards clean electricity flowing into our grids, and into our homes."
    },
    {
      "id":27,
      "question":"Warming is expected to harm much of our wildlife, pushing wilderness to the brink. If it warms by 2 to 3 degrees Celsius, what % of our plants and animals are NOT likely to survive? :",
      "options":["30% to 60%", "20% to 30%", "10% to 20%", "0% to 10%"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"Research shows that we are in the midst of the Sixth Extinction, with recent extinction rates happening at speeds that have not been seen in the last 65 million years. Scientists have already catalogued species migrating â€œuphill and polewardsâ€ in search of cooler places to live. At higher temperature rises of 3.5 to 4 degrees Celsius, the proportion of our wildlife at risk of extinction rises to include 30% to 60% of birds and frogs, and 40% to 60% of corals."
    },
    {
      "id":28,
      "question":"Which of the following is NOT a low-carbon source of energy?:",
      "options":["Solar Power", "Wind Power", "Natural Gas", "Biomass Power"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":2,
      "fact":"According to the United Nations, natural gas releases a median value of 469,000 tonnes of carbon dioxide for every terawatt-hour of energy it generates. While this is LOWER than coal (around 1 million tonnes) and oil (around 840,000 tonnes), it is still much HIGHER than solar (46,000 tonnes), biomass (18,000 tonnes), nuclear (16,000 tonnes), wind (12,000 tonnes) and hydropower (4,000 tonnes).  Natural gas from fracking releases even MORE carbon dioxide, making it as dirty as coal."
    },
    {
      "id":29,
      "question":"â€œIf everyone ate no more than 90g of animal protein (meat, fish, eggs) per day, the global effort needed to stay on track for 2 degrees Celsius would drop by 50%â€. Is this statement true or false? :",
      "options":["False", "True"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"According to the United Nations, switching to this healthy diet, as recommended by the Harvard Medical School, would halve the cost of stabilizing the carbon dioxide in our atmosphere at 450 parts per million. This is the threshold required to limit warming to 2 degrees Celsius. This â€œhealthy dietâ€ limits animal protein to 90g a day, and is complemented by many plant products like vegetables, beans and nuts to provide the full nutrition needed."
    },
    {
      "id":30,
      "question":"What is the average carbon footprint per person in the world in 2011? (includes emissions from burning fossils fuels and making cement, excludes deforestation, forest fires and other land use changes):",
      "options":["17 metric tons", "4.9 metric tons", "7.1 metric tons", "9.3 metric tons"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":1,
      "fact":"According to the World Bank, this is the global average. In comparison, the average American emits 17 tonnes, Australian â€“ 16.5 tonnes, Canadian â€“ 14.1 tonnes, South Korean â€“ 11.8 tonnes, Japanese  â€“ 9.3 tonnes, German â€“ 8.9 tonnes, Malaysian â€“ 7.9 tonnes, New Zealander â€“ 7.1 tonnes, Chinese â€“ 6.7 tonnes, Thai â€“ 4.5 tonnes, Singaporean â€“ 4.3 tonnes, Indonesia â€“ 2.3 tonnes, Vietnamese â€“ 2 tonnes, Indian â€“ 1.7 tonnes, Filipino â€“ 0.9 tonnes, Nigerian â€“ 0.5 tonnes, Kenyan â€“ 0.3 tonnes, Cambodian â€“ 0.3 tonnes and Ugandan â€“ 0.1 tonne.  "
    },
    {
      "id":31,
      "question":"We released 49 billion tonnes of greenhouse gases in 2010. What level do we need to stabilize at for a safe climate? :",
      "options":["25 billion tonnes a year", "40 billion tonnes a year", "100 billion tonnes a year", "Zero"],
      "type":"mcq",
      "answer":3,
      "fact":"In our past, weâ€™ve already pumped in around 2,000 billion tonnes of greenhouse gases into our atmosphere. This means weâ€™ve locked in a certain amount of warming. To avoid the most dangerous futures, we need to stop releasing more greenhouse gases. Many countries are working actively to reduce their emissions over time to zero, from the growing use of electric cars (United States), encouraging citizens to eat 50% less meat (China) and intensive adoption of wind and solar power (Germany, Portugal, Denmark)."
    }
  ]
}